Guide to the Oliver Reiser Papers, 1930-1974 UA.90.F10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, I.
  - Speedie, Gordon (3) (Box 4, Folder 402)
  - Speedie, Gordon (4) (Box 4, Folder 403)
  - Spencer, Herbert L. (Box 4, Folder 404)
  - Stacy, Don (Box 4, Folder 405)
  - Stanicci, Margaret (Box 4, Folder 406)
  - Stehle, Ottmar (Box 4, Folder 407)
  - Steiger, Brad (Box 4, Folder 408)
  - Stewart, Leland (Box 4, Folder 409)
  - Stewart, Rosemarie (Box 4, Folder 410)
  - Stromberg, Gustaf (Box 4, Folder 411)
  - Stulman, Julius (Box 4, Folder 412)
  - Suares, Carlo (Box 4, Folder 413)
  - Subject: Concerning a Proposed International Institute of Cultural Collaboration (Box 4, Folder 414)
  - Sutherland, W.F. (Box 4, Folder 415)
  - Tansley, David (Box 4, Folder 416)
  - Taylor, Glen H. (Box 4, Folder 417)
  - Tead, Orway (Box 4, Folder 418)
  - Thomas, Wendell (Box 4, Folder 419)
  - Thompson, Clara A. (Box 4, Folder 420)
  - Thoreau Foundation, The (Box 4, Folder 421)
  - Tinkham, M. (Box 4, Folder 422)
  - Tipple, Esther Watson (1) (Box 4, Folder 423)
  - Tipple, Esther Watson (2) (Box 4, Folder 424)
  - Tipple, Esther Watson (3) (Box 4, Folder 425)
  - Tomasic, Thomas M. (Box 4, Folder 426)
  - Tracy, Henry C. (Box 4, Folder 427)
  - Trainor, Joseph C. (Box 4, Folder 428)
  - Trammell, Louise (Box 4, Folder 429)
  - Triantafyllou, Triant (Box 4, Folder 430)
  - Trustees of Space (Box 4, Folder 431)
  - Turner, Mary W. (Box 4, Folder 432)
  - Undeck, J.P. (Box 4, Folder 433)
  - United Nations and International Committee on Scientific Humanism (Box 4, Folder 434)
  - United Nations Conference on International Organization (Box 4, Folder 435)
  - UNESCO questionnaire on democracy (Box 4, Folder 436)
  - Unity New York (Box 4, Folder 437)
  - Universal Knowledge Foundation (Box 5, Folder 438)
  - Universities and the Quest for Peace (Box 5, Folder 439)
  - University of Minnesota Press - Conger Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 440)
  - University of Pittsburgh: Administration (Box 5, Folder 441)
  - Utica College (Box 5, Folder 442)
  - Vanderjagt, B.G.H. (1) (Box 5, Folder 443)
  - Vanderjagt, B.G.H. (2) (Box 5, Folder 444)
  - Vanderjagt, B.G.H. (3) (Box 5, Folder 445)
  - Var, Robert E. (Box 5, Folder 446)
  - Vinkenoog, Simon (Box 5, Folder 447)
  - Wagar, W. Warren (Box 5, Folder 448)
  - Watson, David (Box 5, Folder 449)
  - Webster, John (Box 5, Folder 450)
  - Wells, Oliver D. (Box 5, Folder 451)
  - Werkmeister, W.H. (Box 5, Folder 452)
  - Westcott, Roger (Box 5, Folder 453)
  - Wheeler, John (Box 5, Folder 454)
  - Wheeler, Raymond H. (Box 5, Folder 455)
  - White, John (Box 5, Folder 456)
  - Whitman, David (Box 5, Folder 457)
  - Whorf, B.L. (Box 5, Folder 458)
  - Who's Who of World Authors, Lectures, and Artists (Box 5, Folder 459)
  - Widman, Marilyn (Box 5, Folder 460)
  - Willard, Robert L. (Box 5, Folder 461)
  - Wilson, Donna (Box 5, Folder 462)
  - Wilson, Edwin H. (Box 5, Folder 463)
  - Winetrout, Kenneth (Box 5, Folder 464)
  - Winthrop, Henry (Box 5, Folder 465)
  - Woltman, Frederick (Box 5, Folder 466)
  - Women's Universal Movement (Box 5, Folder 467)
  - Woods, Richard G. (Box 5, Folder 468)
  - Woolfenden, Wallace B. (Box 5, Folder 469)
  - Worcester Polytechnic Institute (Box 5, Folder 470)
  - World Conference on Scientific Yoga, The (Box 5, Folder 471)
  - World Constitutional Convention (Box 5, Folder 472)
  - World District Agency (Box 5, Folder 473)
  - Dimensions of the Future (Box 5, Folder 474)
  - World Institute Council (Box 5, Folder 475)
  - World Union International Centre (Box 5, Folder 476)
  - Wou Saofong (Box 5, Folder 477)
  - Yorke, Bruce (Box 5, Folder 478)
  - Young, Arthur M. (Box 5, Folder 479)
  - Youngblood, Gene (Box 5, Folder 480)
  - Zorn, Henry V. (Box 5, Folder 481)
- Publications, II.
  The Publications series contains book reviews, articles, books authored by Reiser, and general publications.
  - Book Reviews, 1.
    This subseries, organized alphabetically by title of reviewed work with the author's name in parentheses, includes manuscripts, published reviews, and sometimes both.
    - The Anatomy of Science (Gilbert N. Lewis) (Box 5, Folder 482)
    - The Concept of Time (Louise Robinson Heath) (Box 5, Folder 483)
    - The Conditions of Philosophy (Mortimer J. Adler) (Box 5, Folder 484)
    - Dimensions of Freedom (Felix Oppenheim) (Box 5, Folder 485)
    - The Dramatic Universe (John G. Bennett) (Box 5, Folder 486)
    - Du Cheminement de la Pensee (Emile Meyerson) (Box 5, Folder 487)
    - ESP and Personality Patterns (Schneidler & McConnell) (Box 5, Folder 488)
    - Ethics and Science (Henry Margenau) (Box 5, Folder 489)
    - From The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science (1952-1968) (Box 5, Folder 490)
    - Happiness, Freedom, and God (C.A. Richardson) (Box 5, Folder 491)
    - Ideas & Opinions (Albert Einstein) (Box 5, Folder 492)
    - The Image of the Future (Fred L. Polak) (Box 5, Folder 493)
    - In Search of Philosophic Understanding (Edwin Burtt) (Box 5, Folder 494)
    - John Dewey in Perspective (George R. Geiger) (Box 5, Folder 495)
    - Language in Action (S.I. Hayakawa) (Box 5, Folder 496)
    - The Living Stream (Sir Alastair Hardy) (Box 5, Folder 497)
    - The Logic of Liberty (Michael Polanyi) (Box 5, Folder 498)
    - Meaning and Necessity (Rudolf Carnap) (Box 5, Folder 499)
    - Modern Experiments in Telepathy (S.G. Soal and Frederick Bateman) (Box 5, Folder 500)
    - Nationalism and the Communal Mind (E. Hanbury Hankin) (Box 5, Folder 501)
    - Natural Rights & History (Leo Strauss) (Box 5, Folder 502)
    - New Humanism, A Manifesto (M.N. Roy) (Box 5, Folder 503)
    - Philosophy in a New Key (Susanne Langer) (Box 5, Folder 504)
    - The Planetarization of Consciousness (Dane Rudhyar) (Box 5, Folder 505)
    - Principles of Gestalty Psychology (Kurt Koffka) (Box 5, Folder 506)
    - The Reach of the Mind (J.B. Rhine) (Box 5, Folder 507)
    - The Scientific Adventure (Herbert Dingle) (Box 5, Folder 508)
    - Scientific Humanism and ESP Research: On Extra-Sensory Perception After Sixty Years (J.B. Rhine) (Box 5, Folder 509)
    - Search for Truth (Eric T. Bell) (Box 5, Folder 510)
    - The Shining Stranger (Preston Harold) (Box 5, Folder 511)
    - A Treatise on Induction and Probability (Von Wright, George Henrik) (Box 5, Folder 512)
    - Ventures in Social Change (Henry Winthrop) (Box 5, Folder 513)
  - Articles, 2.
    This subseries, organized alphabetically by article title, includes manuscripts, published reviews, and sometimes both.
    - "An Archetype for World Philosophy" (Box 5, Folder 514)
    - "Astrobiology" (Box 5, Folder 514a)
    - "Brain Waves, Astrophysics, and Consciousness" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 515)
    - "Building the World Sensorium" (Box 5, Folder 516)
    - "Cosmic Guiding Fields" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 517)
    - "Creativity As Education's Core" (Box 5, Folder 518)
    - "The Cultural Crisis in America" (Box 5, Folder 519)
    - "Does Mankind Need a World Religion?" (Box 5, Folder 520)
    - "The Emergence of the World Sensorium" (Box 5, Folder 521)
    - "Escape from Chaos" (Box 5, Folder 521a)
    - "The Evolution of Democracy" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 522)
    - "Evolutionary Humanism and Global Communication" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 523)
    - "Field Theory in Physics and Psychics" (Box 5, Folder 524)
    - "Field Theory of Matter in a Pantheistic Cosmology" (Box 5, Folder 524a)
    - "Fire-Philosophy" (Box 5, Folder 524b)
    - "From Classical Physical to Modern Scientific Assumptions" (Box 5, Folder 525)
    - "From Diogenes to the 'New Left' -- And Beyond" (Box 5, Folder 526)
    - "Human Values in the Coming Society" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 527)
    - "A Humanistic Conception of the Soul" (Box 5, Folder 528)
    - "The Integration of Knowledge" (Box 5, Folder 528a)
    - "Logic, Cybernetics, and General Semantics" (Box 5, Folder 529)
    - "Man's Consciousness in Cosmic Humanism" (Box 5, Folder 530)
    - "Man's Image of the Galaxy" (Box 5, Folder 531)
    - "Matter, Anti-Matter, and Cosmic Symmetry" (Box 5, Folder 532)
    - "A Mental Pattern for the Planet" (Box 5, Folder 533)
    - "Non-Aristotelian Logic and the Crisis in Science" (Box 5, Folder 534)
    - "Our World in Revolution" (Box 5, Folder 535)
    - "Pantheism: The Religion of Science" (Box 5, Folder 536)
    - "A Philosophy for World Unification" (Box 5, Folder 537)
    - "Physics, Probability, and Multi-Valued Logic" (Box 5, Folder 538)
    - "Postulates for an Ethics of Belief in Science, Religion, and Philosophy" (Box 5, Folder 538a)
    - "Questions and Answers on a New Social Structure" (Box 5, Folder 539)
    - "References in Logic and Philosophy of Science" (Box 5, Folder 540)
    - "Religion and Science in Conflict" (Box 5, Folder 541)
    - "Religion, Science, and Ethics from the Standpoint of Scientific Humanism" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 542)
    - "The Role of Symbols in Human Existence" (Box 5, Folder 543)
    - "Scientific Humanism as a Basis for World Unity" (Box 5, Folder 544)
    - "Scientific Humanism as Creative Morality" (Box 5, Folder 545)
    - "Scientific Humanism: A Formulation" (Box 5, Folder 546)
    - "Scientific Method -- One or Many?" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 547)
    - 'Search for the Intention of Creation" (Box 5, Folder 548)
    - "Social Synthesis Via the Integration of Knowledge" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 549)
    - "Some Reflections on Art and Music Education" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 550)
    - "Sri Aurobindo's 'Supramental Light' and 'The Cosmic Lens'" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 551)
    - "The Twilight of Dreams & Aurora" (Box 5, Folder 552)
    - "What is Cosmic Humanism?" (Box 5, Folder 553)
    - "What Is Wrong With Our Civilization?" (Box 5, Folder 554)
    - "World Philosophy and the Integration of Knowledge" (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 555)
  - Reiser Books, 3.
    This subseries contains two complete Reiser-authored manuscripts and pieces of his other books, some identified and some unidentified, in varied states of completion.
    - Book Chapter: From Astrophysics to Cosmic Humanism (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 556)
    - Book Chapter: Religion in Philosophical and Cultural Perspective (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 557)
    - Book Chapter: The Alchemy of Energy (Box 5, Folder 558)
    - Book Chapter: The Eternal Saki (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 559)
    - Chapter I: Wellsprings of Philosophy (manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 560)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (1) (Box 5, Folder 561)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (2) (Box 5, Folder 562)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (3) (Box 5, Folder 563)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (4) (Box 5, Folder 564)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (5) (Box 5, Folder 565)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (6) (Box 5, Folder 566)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (7) (Box 5, Folder 567)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (8) (Box 5, Folder 568)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (9) (Box 5, Folder 569)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (10) (Box 6, Folder 570)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (11) (Box 6, Folder 571)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (12) (Box 6, Folder 572)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (13) (Box 6, Folder 573)
    - Cosmic Humanism - Manuscript (14) (Box 6, Folder 574)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Galley Proof (Box 6, Folder 575)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (1) (Box 6, Folder 576)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (2) (Box 6, Folder 577)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (3) (Box 6, Folder 578)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (4) (Box 6, Folder 579)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (5) (Box 6, Folder 580)
    - Cosmic Humanism and World Unity - Manuscript (6) (Box 6, Folder 581)
    - Epilogue on Spherical Harmonics (Box 6, Folder 582)
    - Epilogue: The Song of Saki (Box 6, Folder 583)
    - Marked pages removed from Philosophy and Concepts of Modern Science (Box 6, Folder 584)
    - Pieces of unidentified manuscript(s) (Box 6, Folder 585)
    - Religion from the Standpoint of Scientific Humanism (Box 6, Folder 586)
    - Table of Contents and Introduction to unidentified work (Box 6, Folder 586a)
    - Prologue on the Spiral Urge (Box 6, Folder 586b)
    - The Logic of Gestalt Psychology (Box 12, Folder 824)
  - General, 4.
    This subseries includes letters to newspapers, published statements (e.g. "Man's highest mission..."), loose abstracts and diagrams from Reiser publications, prefaces to other authors' books, and monographs.
    - "Can We Learn from the Riots?" (statement published in Change) (Box 6, Folder 587)
    - Dissertation on Creative Monism: Abstract (Box 6, Folder 588)
    - Humanist Talk for New York (Box 6, Folder 589)
    - "Language & World Order" (Symposium Address) (Box 6, Folder 590)
    - Loose diagrams (Box 6, Folder 591)
    - "Man's highest mission…" (Box 6, Folder 592)
    - Monograph on Merton S. Kingston (manuscript) (Box 6, Folder 593)
    - Naturalistic Humanism as a Basis for a World Philosophy: Abstract (Box 6, Folder 594)
    - Preface to Education in the New Age (Alice A. Bailey) (Box 6, Folder 595)
    - Project Prometheus Materials, Some correspondence and newspaper articles have been kept in this folder for context. (Box 6, Folder 596)
    - Remarks on "Science and Peace" (Box 6, Folder 597)
    - "U.S. Not Founded on Religious Principles, Bible Backers Told" (Box 6, Folder 598)
    - Unified Symbolism for World Understanding in Science (Box 6, Folder 599)
    - Whorf-Reiser exchange in Main Currents 1948 vol. 6 (Box 6, Folder 600)
    - The World University (Box 6, Folder 601)
- Personal Papers, III.
  The Personal Papers series contains folders, notes, course materials, event materials, newspaper clippings, awards, notebooks, galleys for other authors' books, and general material.
  - Folders, 1.
    This subseries contains thematically organized articles, book excerpts, and notes put together by Reiser and dealing with disparate subjects. Contents are as Reiser left them.
    - 8-Fold Way & Particles (Box 6, Folder 602)
    - Advanced Logic (Box 6, Folder 603)
    - American Philosophy (Box 6, Folder 604)
    - Aristotle's Cosmology (Box 6, Folder 605)
    - Atlantis (Box 6, Folder 606)
    - Atomic Hydrogen & Galaxies (Box 6, Folder 607)
    - Babcock & Kozyrev (Box 6, Folder 608)
    - Bentham & Mill (Box 6, Folder 609)
    - Bergson & The New Realism (Box 6, Folder 610)
    - Biological Clocks, Time-Paradox, Asymmetry (Box 6, Folder 611)
    - Black Holes John Wheeler & Weber's Gravity Waves (Box 6, Folder 612)
    - Book Excerpt & Notes on Vision & Psychophysics (Box 6, Folder 613)
    - Brain Waves and Altered Consciousness (Box 6, Folder 614)
    - Coming of the WSV Cosmic… (1) (Box 6, Folder 615)
    - Coming of the WSV Cosmic… (2) (Box 6, Folder 616)
    - Concepts of Modern Thought (Box 6, Folder 617)
    - Cosmology (Box 6, Folder 618)
    - Creative Morality (Box 6, Folder 619)
    - Descartes & Bacon (Box 7, Folder 620)
    - Early Civilizations (Box 7, Folder 621)
    - Early Civilizations Old & New World (Box 7, Folder 622)
    - Earth Atmosphere & Tectonics, The (Box 7, Folder 623)
    - Elementary Particles (Box 7, Folder 624)
    - Esther Watson Tipple (Box 7, Folder 625)
    - Ethics (Box 7, Folder 626)
    - Field Theory (Box 7, Folder 627)
    - Folder on black holes (Box 7, Folder 628)
    - Geological Field Reversals (Box 7, Folder 629)
    - Geology (Box 7, Folder 630)
    - Glastonbury Project (1), Possibly related to Reiser book This Holyest Erthe (Box 7, Folder 631)
    - Glastonbury Project (2), Possibly related to Reiser book This Holyest Erthe (Box 7, Folder 632)
    - Glastonbury Project (3), Possibly related to Reiser book This Holyest Erthe (Box 7, Folder 633)
    - Glastonbury Project (4), Possibly related to Reiser book This Holyest Erthe (Box 7, Folder 634)
    - GS Newsletter (Box 7, Folder 635)
    - Helium and Superconductivity (Box 7, Folder 636)
    - Helium Earth & Sun (Box 7, Folder 637)
    - History of Science (Box 7, Folder 638)
    - Integration (Box 7, Folder 639)
    - Interdisciplinarity (Box 7, Folder 640)
    - Introduction to Philosophy (Box 7, Folder 641)
    - Israelites & Judaism (Box 7, Folder 642)
    - Kant & Hegel (Box 7, Folder 643)
    - Keith and White Correspondence on Dimensions (Box 7, Folder 644)
    - Leftovers from Cosmic Humanism & Blodwen's article (Box 7, Folder 645)
    - Light & Vision (Box 7, Folder 646)
    - Living Philosophers (Box 7, Folder 647)
    - Logic & Probability (Box 7, Folder 648)
    - Magnetaplasm, Radiation Belts & Earth as a Dynamo (Box 7, Folder 649)
    - Magnetism (Box 7, Folder 650)
    - Man in the Americas (Box 7, Folder 651)
    - Medieval Philosophy & Beginnings of Modern Thought (Box 7, Folder 652)
    - Mercator, 53 Tone, Equal Temperament and International Pitch (Box 7, Folder 653)
    - Music Logarithmic Spiral (Box 7, Folder 654)
    - Nervous System (Box 7, Folder 655)
    - New Book & Tipple Article (Box 7, Folder 656)
    - New Particles (Box 7, Folder 657)
    - Oriental Philosophers (Box 7, Folder 658)
    - Origin and Migrations of the Indo-Europeans (Box 7, Folder 659)
    - Origin of Life (Box 7, Folder 660)
    - Pantheism (Box 8, Folder 661)
    - Phenomenology & Relativity (Box 8, Folder 662)
    - Philosophy & History of Science (Box 8, Folder 663)
    - Philosophy (Box 8, Folder 664)
    - Philosophy 8 (Box 8, Folder 665)
    - Philosophy of Education (Box 8, Folder 666)
    - Philosophy of Energetics (Box 8, Folder 667)
    - The Philosophy of John Dewey (Box 8, Folder 668)
    - Philosophy of Religion (1) (Box 8, Folder 669)
    - Philosophy of Religion (2) (Box 8, Folder 670)
    - Philosophy of Religion (3) (Box 8, Folder 671)
    - The Philosophy of the Science of Music (Box 8, Folder 672)
    - Plato's Republic (Box 8, Folder 673)
    - Pre-History (Box 8, Folder 674)
    - Quasars (Box 8, Folder 675)
    - Religions of the World (Box 8, Folder 676)
    - Religious Mysticism - Zen & Gandhi (Box 8, Folder 677)
    - Reviews of Reiser's work (Box 8, Folder 678)
    - The Role of Philosophy in Civilization (Box 8, Folder 679)
    - Royce (Box 8, Folder 680)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (1) (Box 8, Folder 681)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (2) (Box 8, Folder 682)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (3) (Box 8, Folder 683)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (4) (Box 8, Folder 684)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (5) (Box 8, Folder 685)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (6) (Box 8, Folder 686)
    - S.C. Dodd Educational Materials (7) (Box 8, Folder 687)
    - Science & Humanism (Box 8, Folder 688)
    - Science & Humanism - Zoroastrianism (Box 8, Folder 689)
    - Scientific Humanism (Box 8, Folder 690)
    - Semantics (Box 8, Folder 691)
    - Spirals (Box 8, Folder 692)
    - Stonehedge & Ireland (Box 8, Folder 693)
    - Superconductivity & Superfluids (Box 8, Folder 694)
    - Time & History (Box 8, Folder 695)
    - William James (Box 8, Folder 696)
    - World Sensorium Material (Box 8, Folder 697)
  - Notes, 2.
    This subseries contains Reiser's notes on a range of topics organized by headings when present or inferable. Loose notes without headings are filed under Assorted Notes.
    - Aesthetics in Science & Religion (Box 8, Folder 698)
    - An Integrated Systems Theory (Box 8, Folder 699)
    - Assorted Notes (1) (Box 8, Folder 700)
    - Assorted Notes (2) (Box 8, Folder 701)
    - Assorted Notes (3) (Box 8, Folder 702)
    - Assorted Notes (4) (Box 8, Folder 703)
    - Assorted Notes (5) (Box 8, Folder 704)
    - Bertrand Russell (Box 8, Folder 705)
    - Bibliography on Humanism (Box 9, Folder 706)
    - Biochemical Reaction Velocities & Psychic Time (Box 9, Folder 707)
    - Brief Bibliography on Readable Books (Box 9, Folder 708)
    - Comparing Aristotle, Francis Bacon, Bertrand Russell, John Dewey, J.S. Mill (Box 9, Folder 709)
    - Consciousness, Radiation and the Developing Sensory System (Box 9, Folder 710)
    - Cosmic Humanism - What Is It? (Box 9, Folder 711)
    - ESP Research (Box 9, Folder 712)
    - Existentialism (Box 9, Folder 713)
    - The Hebrew-Christian Religious Tradition (Box 9, Folder 714)
    - Hinduism (Box 9, Folder 715)
    - History of Semantics (Box 9, Folder 716)
    - Hixen Symposium (Box 9, Folder 717)
    - Humanism as a Technology (Box 9, Folder 718)
    - Huxley-Barnes Debate (Box 9, Folder 719)
    - Indo-Europeans ("Aryans") (Box 9, Folder 720)
    - Jungian Archetypes - Some Questions (Box 9, Folder 721)
    - Karl Marx (Box 9, Folder 722)
    - Key Periodic Table, sKs, Generating Cosmic Constants (Box 9, Folder 723)
    - Notes toward article for Thanatology, Dean University, and Harold Symposium (Box 9, Folder 724)
    - On Evolution (Box 9, Folder 725)
    - On Music (Box 9, Folder 726)
    - Orgone Energy Weather Engineering, The Law, and the Environmental Crisis (Box 9, Folder 727)
    - Philosophical Aspects of Language and Communication (Box 9, Folder 728)
    - Philosophy of Religion: Descartes & Mind-Body Problem (Box 9, Folder 729)
    - Planetary Man and Cosmic Guiding Fields (Box 9, Folder 730)
    - Problem of Knowledge (Box 9, Folder 731)
    - Religion in the Public Schools (Box 9, Folder 732)
    - Semantics & Cybernetics (Box 9, Folder 733)
    - Talk on Man's New Image of Man (Box 9, Folder 734)
    - The Universe Between Your Ears (Box 9, Folder 735)
    - The Unknown Life of Jesus Christ (Box 9, Folder 736)
  - Course Materials, 3.
    This subseries contains course materials and includes announcements, syllabi, and course outlines.
    - Announcements (Box 9, Folder 737)
    - From Primitive Magic to Modern Science Lecture Outline (Box 9, Folder 738)
    - Philosophy of Religion Outline (Box 9, Folder 739)
    - Role of Philosophy in Civilization Outline (Box 9, Folder 740)
    - Syllabus for S 191: The Role of Communications in Human Relations (Box 9, Folder 741)
  - Event Materials, 4.
    This subseries contains event materials for conferences, symposiums, lectures, and interview materials.
    - 1970 American Anthropological Association Cultural Futurology Symposium: Pre-Conference Volume (Box 9, Folder 742)
    - 1971 American Anthropological Association Experimental Symposium on Cultural Futurology: Pre-Conference Volume (Box 9, Folder 743)
    - Assorted Event Materials (1) (Box 9, Folder 744)
    - Assorted Event Materials (2) (Box 9, Folder 745)
    - Comments at the Graduate Seminar (Box 9, Folder 746)
    - Production Script for Radio Show on Peace (Box 9, Folder 747)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 5.
    This subseries contains both clippings on Reiser and clippings Reiser kept for reference.
    - Newspaper articles on Reiser & other promotional material (Box 10, Folder 790)
    - "Book on Scientific Humanism Wins Recognition for Dr. Reiser" (Pitt Evening News) (Box 12, Folder 804)
    - Chomsky Clippings (Box 12, Folder 805)
    - "Daedalus or Icarus?" (Madras article on Reiser) (Box 12, Folder 806)
    - "New Satellite Will Help Pave the Way for Communication System" (Box 12, Folder 807)
    - Particle Physics Clipping (Box 12, Folder 808)
    - "Pitt Philosopher's Book Presents Challenging Theme Clearly" (Pittsburgh Press Review) (Box 12, Folder 809)
    - Reiser Citation in 12 Mars 1937 Journal des debats (Box 12, Folder 810)
    - World Culture Needed (Reiser letter to The Times) (Box 12, Folder 811)
  - Awards, 6.
    This subseries contains awards Reiser received.
    - 1969 Fellow of the American Humanist Association Plaque (Box 13, Folder 820)
    - 1973 Humanist Pioneer Award Plaque (Box 13, Folder 821)
    - 1973 Men of Achievement Diploma (Box 13, Folder 822)
  - Notebooks, 7.